CHAD R. RADER DIGITAL MARKETING

Indianapolis, IN 731.412.8223 <u>chad@iamchadrader.com</u> okedIN.com/in/chadrrader

LinkedIN.com/in/chadrrader
Twitter:@crader12

EDUCATION

B. S., Business Management, 2013Columbia Southern University,
Orange Beach, AL

A. S., Business Administration, 2012 Columbia Southern University, Orange Beach, AL

SPECIAL TRAINING

- Project Management Professional (PMP)
- Certified CrossFit Level 1 Trainer
- Top 10% in U.S. Army's Primary Leadership Development Course
- Manager Development Course and Supervisor Development Course while in U.S. Army
- First Aid/CPR/AED certified until 8/2016, Certificate ID: GQP213
- Bloodborne Pathogens certified until 8/2015, Certificate ID: GQP213

ABOUT ME

More than 13 years of experience in management with a strong focus on project planning, processes and execution. Results oriented Internet marketer with strength in vlogging, video production and editing, social media marketing, consumer engagement, community building and online advertising with a documented record of success in increasing sales, online presence and brand awareness using social media platforms.

Key Results:

- Co-creator of online reality show GabeBabeTV on YouTube
- Increased subscribers from 1,000 to 100,000 in less than two years
- \bullet Awarded 100,000 subscribers YouTube honor and named Mr. and Mrs. YouTube 2014
- Boosted viewership to 162,000 subscribers averaging 1.5 million views per month with more than over 27,000,000 views to date
- Created several videos and contests that went viral, driving enormous web traffic and garnering support of national brands such as Walmart, Google (Cool School), Honda, Belkin, Lipton, Fandango, Schick, Saturday Night Live (SNL), Opinions Outpost, Audible, Jimmy Kimmel, HuluPlus, Plated.com, NatureBox, Ulive.com, Fix My Choir TV Show, UNO Dare game, JibJab, Hello Santa, Blue Apron, The Honest Company, Scentbird, Casper, 50 Shades DVD Release, CreditKarma.com, Crème of Nature, RetailMeNot.com and Travel Channel
- Grew social media following to more than 20,000 people on Twitter and Instagram with average likes/engagements of 1,500-2,000 per post

EXPERTISE

- Audio/Video Editing
- Brand Building
- Budgeting/Planning
- Content Creation
- Content Marketing
- Conversion Optimization
- Customer Engagement
- Digital Marketing Strategy
- Emerging Technologies
- Lead Generation
- Project Management
- Social Media Marketing
- Strategic Planning
- SEO/SEM
- Vlogging/Podcasts
- Video Production
- Web Analytics
- Web 2.0

CONFERENCES & PRESENTATIONS

- VloggerFair, August 2014 in Seattle- Featured Guest and Panelist
- PlayList Live, March 2015 in Orlando- Featured Guest and Panelist
- **Proctor & Gamble Pampers Baby Board Event,** June 2015 in Cincinnati 1 of 3 vloggers selected to represent P&G Pampers products
- Vidcon, July 2015 in Anaheim- Featured Guest
- VloqqerFair, August 2015 in Seattle- Featured Guest and Panelist

CHAD R. RADER DIGITAL MARKETING

Indianapolis, IN 731.412.8223 <u>chad@iamchadrader.com</u> <u>LinkedIN.com/in/chadrrader</u> Twitter:@crader12

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CG Entertainment, LLC dba GabeBabeTV, Indianapolis, IN 2011 - present

Owner/Creator/Social Media Strategist

Digital content creator (video, motion graphics, interactive media, online advertisements) for video blog / online reality TV show. Launched first coordinated social media effort as a means to generate brand awareness and develop leads. Co-manages all online marketing efforts. Digital marketing duties include: special media marketing, engaging visitors, building community, SEO, vlog script development, arranging video shoots, managing talent and external vendors, shooting video for publication, editing footage, and tracking all digital media projects. Works on average of 5-10 initiatives concurrently.

Key Performance Results:

- Co-creator of online reality show GabeBabeTV on YouTube
- Increased subscribers from 1,000 to 100,000 in less than two years
- Awarded 100,000 subscribers YouTube honor and named Mr. and Mrs. YouTube 2014
- Boosted viewership to 162,000 subscribers averaging 1.5 million views per month with more than over 27,000,000 views to date
- Created several videos and contests that went viral, driving enormous web traffic and garnering support of national brands such as Walmart, Google (Cool School), Honda, Belkin, Lipton, Fandango, Schick, Saturday Night Live (SNL), Opinions Outpost, Audible, Jimmy Kimmel, HuluPlus, Plated.com, NatureBox, Ulive.com, Fix My Choir TV Show, UNO Dare game, JibJab, Hello Santa, Blue Apron, The Honest Company, Scentbird, Casper, 50 Shades DVD Release, CreditKarma.com, Crème of Nature, RetailMeNot.com and Travel Channel
- Grew social media following to more than 20,000 people on Twitter and Instagram with average likes/engagements of 1,500-2,000 per post

ISR Group, Inc., Savannah, TN 2008 - 2013

The number one provider of ISR support services worldwide

Scan Eagle UAS Field Services Representative (FSR) Manager/Instructor Director of Technical Services and Training Systems

Served as second in command to the Chief Operations Officer (COO) as a manager and instructor with "secret" level security clearance responsible for supervising more than 200 employees spread over 12 different deployed combat locations. Instructor in charge of training fully qualified field service representatives in support of OEF (Afghanistan), and OIF/OND (Iraq) and 18 Scan Eagle FSRs as the primary flight instructor during their Scan Eagle Operator course. Effectively worked with cross-functional teams to ensure maximum company profitability by assisting with budget planning, management and creating sales presentations to earn future business opportunities. Planned and attended industry trade shows to promote the organizational business model.

Key Performance Results:

- Increased revenue by managing hiring process for more than 20 new annual deployed positions supporting Prime Contractor
- Managed and maintained over \$13 Million of mission essential parts and supplies from deployed combat location
- Awarded human resources honor "Field Service Representative of the Month" by Prime Contractor while deployed in support
 of the US Air Force
- Designated as one of few sub contractors to serve as Scan Eagle Theatre/Logistics lead
- Trusted by leadership to supervise \$500K budget and ensure maximum company profitability

United States Army (active duty), Arizona, Louisiana, Georgia 2000 - 2007

Squad Leader/Sergeant (Non-Commissioned Officer)/Hunter UAS Standardization Instructor Pilot

- Held "secret" security clearance; initial security clearance granted in 2001
- · Built and maintained Unit Standard Operating Procedures (SOP) with Commander's authority
- Upheld Army, FAA, Unit and UAV rules and regulations by enforcing them with soldiers in the unit
- Lead progression, currency, and testing of unit's UAV Pilots maintaining unit readiness at 100%
- Served as Lead Maintenance Test Pilot testing all aspects of new or rebuilt Hunter UAVs
- Trained and qualified more than 30 crew chiefs to support ground operations on Hunter UAS
- Unit Master Driver in charge of qualifying over 50 soldiers on the operation and safety of multiple vehicles
- Served as Unit Safety Officer in charge of creating a safe work environment at all times

Key Performance Results:

- Ranked in top 10% of Primary Leadership Development Course (PLDC) earning Commandants List Award
- Earned two Army Good Conduct Medals while in service